Shirley is a drama, thriller, mystery film directed by Josephine Decker.
A famous horror writer finds inspiration for her next book
after she and her husband take in a young couple.
Shirley Jackson, played by Elisabeth Moss.
Rose Nemser / Paula, played by Odessa Young.
Stanley Hyman, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Fred Nemser, played by Logan Lerman.
Katherine, played by Victoria Pedretti.
Randy Fisher, played by Robert Wuhl.
Shirley is a 2020 American biographical drama film directed by Josephine Decker from a screenplay by Sarah Gubbins, based on the 2014 novel by Susan Scarf
Merrell, which formed a "largely fictional story" around novelist Shirley Jackson during the time period she was writing her 1951 novel Hangsaman.
The film stars Elisabeth Moss as Jackson, with Michael Stuhlbarg,
Odessa Young, and Logan Lerman in supporting roles.
Martin Scorsese serves as an executive producer.
Shirley had its world premiere at the Sundance Film Festival on January 25, 2020,
where Decker won the Special Jury Award for Auteur Filmmaking.
The film was released in the United States on June 5, 2020, to
positive reviews, with praise for Moss's performance.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
biography, writer, woman director, young couple.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.